This is the end...
Apocalypse Now is a drama, war film directed by Francis Ford Coppola.
At the height of the Vietnam war, Captain Benjamin Willard is sent on a dangerous mission that, officially, "does not exist, nor will it ever exist." His goal is to locate -
and eliminate - a mysterious Green Beret Colonel named Walter Kurtz, who has been leading his personal army on illegal guerrilla missions into enemy territory.
Captain Benjamin Willard, played by Martin Sheen.
Colonel Walter Kurtz, played by Marlon Brando.
Jay 'Chef' Hicks, played by Frederic Forrest.
Chief Phillips, played by Albert Hall.
Tyrone 'Clean' Miller, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Lance B. Johnson, played by Sam Bottoms.
Apocalypse Now is a 1979 American psychological epic war film produced and
directed by Francis Ford Coppola (credited as Francis Coppola).
The screenplay, written by Coppola and John Milius, with narration by Michael Herr, is loosely inspired by the 1899 novella
Heart of Darkness by Joseph Conrad, with the setting changed from late 19th-century Congo to the Vietnam War.
The film follows a river journey from South Vietnam into Cambodia undertaken by Captain Willard (Martin Sheen), who is on a secret mission to
assassinate Colonel Kurtz (Marlon Brando), a renegade Special Forces officer who is accused of murder and presumed insane.
The ensemble cast also features Robert Duvall, Frederic Forrest, Albert Hall, Sam
Bottoms, Laurence Fishburne, Dennis Hopper, and Harrison Ford.
Milius became interested in adapting Heart of Darkness for a Vietnam War setting in the late 1960s, and
initially began developing the film with Coppola as producer and George Lucas as director.
After Lucas became unavailable, Coppola took over directorial control, and was influenced by
Werner Herzog's Aguirre, the Wrath of God (1972) in his approach to the material.
Initially set to be a five-month shoot in the Philippines starting in March
1976, a series of problems lengthened it to over a year.
These problems included expensive sets being destroyed by severe weather, Brando showing up on set overweight and
completely unprepared, and Sheen having a breakdown and suffering a near-fatal heart attack on location.
After photography was finally finished in May 1977, the release was postponed
several times while Coppola edited over a million feet of film.
Many of these difficulties are chronicled in the documentary
Hearts of Darkness: A Filmmaker's Apocalypse (1991).
Apocalypse Now was honored with the Palme d'Or at the Cannes
Film Festival, where it premiered unfinished.
When it was finally released on August 15, 1979, by United Artists, it performed well at the box
office, grossing $80 million in the United States and Canada and $150 million worldwide.
Initial reviews were polarized; while Vittorio Storaro's cinematography was widely acclaimed, several critics
found Coppola's handling of the story's major themes anticlimactic and intellectually disappointing.
The film was nominated for eight Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director (Coppola), and
Best Supporting Actor (Duvall); it went on to win Best Cinematography and Best Sound.
Apocalypse Now has been assessed as Coppola's magnum opus and
retrospectively considered one of the greatest films ever made.
In 2000, the film was selected for preservation in
the National Film Registry by the U.S.
Library of Congress as "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant".
Coppola later released Apocalypse Now Redux, an extended re-edit of
the film that contains multiple new scenes, in 2001.
Another re-edit, Apocalypse Now Final Cut, was released in 2019
and is Coppola's preferred version of the film.
The film explores themes of guerrilla warfare,
vietnam war, journalist, mission, vietnam.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.